

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER . CLOUD ENTHUSIAST

Edmonton, Alberta, Canada

🛮 (+1) 587-877-7147 | 🔀 colemackenzie1@gmail.com | 🏕 https://cmackenzie1.github.io | 🖸 cmackenzie1 | 🛅 cole-mackenzie

Summary _

Current Student at the University of Alberta pursuing a Bachelor of Science with Specialization in Computing Science. I have 2 years of experience in back-end development, infrastructure automation, and system operations at Intuit where I completed a 16 month Co-op and also completed 1 patent submission with 4 others members of my team. I am always interested in learning new (and old) technologies and applying them to my current projects.

Skills

Interested in the good stuff? These are the languages, technologies and tools I have worked with

Languages: Java (Spring), Python, Ruby (Chef), Go, C

Tools: Amazon Web Services (EC2, IAM, S3, Route53, VPC, RDS, CloudWatch, CloudFormation), Docker, Git, Jenkins, Terraform, CircleCI, Splunk, Grafana

Databases: MySQL, Elastic Search, DynamoDB, Neo4j

Operating Systems: macOS (Mac OS X), Linux (most experienced in RHEL, Amazon Linux, and Ubuntu)

Work Experience

Intuit Inc.

Mountain View, California

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN May. 2018 - PRESENT

- Architected and developed an application built on the Spring Framework
- · Implemented a pipeline to export, validate, and migrate Amazon Connect call flows between environments and regions.
- Visualized Amazon Connect contact flow dependencies and impact radius using Neo4j graph database

Intuit Inc. Edmonton, Alberta

Software Developer Co-op

Jan. 2017 - April. 2018

- Simplified our development environment for our Python application by utilizing Docker containers and Docker Compose
- Built and deployed overall service infrastructure utilizing Docker container, AWS CodeBuild, and several other AWS services (Including EC2, ECS, Route 53, S3, CloudFront, RDS, IAM), focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- Spearheaded a service migration from our internal data center to AWS using well established and industry best practices
- Delivered on going System Operations for our services in AWS and was responsible for several production and development AWS accounts.
- Volunteered for on-site support during high traffic periods and exceeded multiple managers expectations for the level of service provided.

Fraunhofer FOKUS Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

June. 2016 - July. 2016

- Tested and evaluated InfluxDB and Elastic Search for storing time-series data from Health Accessories (ie. Fitbit) and EKG (Electrocardiogram) tests.
- Created dashboards in Kibana and Grafana for visualizing collected metrics.
- Devised a simple RESTful API with Apache NiFi with custom processors for data processing.
- Created Docker containers and required scripts for containerization of Apache NiFi.

Education

University of Alberta Edmonton, Alberta

B.Sc. IN COMPUTING SCIENCE WITH SPECIALIZATION

Sept. 2014 - present

Co-op program with 16-months experience

Extracurricular Activity _____

Ada's Team Edmonton, Alberta

MEMBER Sept. 2015 - PRESENT

• http://www.adasteam.ca/ - A group of students at the University of Alberta dedicated to promoting diversity in computing, games, and technology.

JULY 27, 2018 COLE MACKENZIE · RÉSUMÉ

Undergraduate Association of Computing Science (UACS)

Edmonton, Alberta

Member Sept. 2014 - PRESENT

• The purpose of UACS is to promote an environment for the interaction of computing science students with other computing science students and other relevant parties.

Lambda Chi Alpha Mens Fraternity

Edmonton, Alberta

VICE PRESIDENT

Oct. 2016 - Apr. 2017, May. 2018 - PRESENT

- Created plans to involve all brothers in the Chapter's programming and operations through the use of teams, committees, and incentive programs to maximize participation
- Acted as the Chapter's second ranking officer, replacing the President in his absence or inability to function.
- Served as strictly an advisement role for our Executive Committee.

Lambda Chi Alpha Mens Fraternity

Edmonton, Alberta

PRESIDENT

May. 2017 - Apr. 2018

- · Served as the executive head of the Chapter by presiding over all chapter meetings and the Executive Committee.
- Enforced the laws and policies of the Fraternity and host institution by seeing that the other elected and appointed officers execute their duties properly and effectively
- Digitized and centralized all our operating documents.
- Fostered leadership skills in the other executives and Chapter members.
- · Championed the fulfilment of our vacant alumni advisory member with a member well recognized by our Chapter.
- Attended several leadership conferences hosted by our International organization.